# Thyraellis Howard

2304 Rosetta St. Richmond VA 23223 Cell Phone: 804-687-2625 thyrahoward@outlook.com

# **Summary of Qualifications**

Hardworking individual with a growing passion in building software, writing code, and programming. Experience working in group projects and completing tasks quickly and efficiently. Additional knowledge includes:

**Software Languages:** HTML, CSS, JavaScript, C, C++, C#, Angular JS, SQL, Knockout JS, Java, PHP **Software Applications:** Microsoft Office, Pixlr, Dreamweaver, Notepad++, Visual Studio 2015-2017, Square Space, GoDaddy web builder, Wix, MySql Workbench, Oracle, Eclipse Java Oxygen, Azure, Android Studio, MongoDB, Github, Slack, Trello, Build Fire, MySql server, Apache, Figma, WordPress

#### **Education**

**ECPI University**, Glen Allen, VA 23060 | February 2018 *Bachelor of Science in Computer and Information Science* Concentration: Software Development

Richmond Technical Center, Richmond, VA 23230 | June 2013

Certificate of Completion: Computer Electronics I & II

Portfolio of Projects: <a href="https://softwarecake.github.io/">https://softwarecake.github.io/</a>

#### **Work Experience**

### Front-End Research Developer, Baylyn Media Services, March 2018 - April 2018

- Research code to improve template designs for websites
- Improved website designs for WordPress sites

### Front-End Developer Extern, Think of Us | November 2016 - March 2018

- Research code to complete tasks for app design
- Develop additional skills in CSS and Backend Development
- Work with team members to implement new processes into existing mobile platforms and adjust old platforms
- Partnered with design team to create a new layout for the teen parent website
- Performed work in Figma and used Slack to communicate on projects
- Used WordPress to design website for clients
- Participated in hack-a-thons such New York Hack Foster Care and Think of Us hack-a-thon

### Food and Service Worker, McDonalds | June 2015- Present

- Utilize quick thinking skills by taking and processing customer orders
- Provide excellent customer service to customers

### Upward Bound Volunteer, Lucille M. Brown Bowl | June 2012- May 2014

- Learned that preparation and timing must be consistent in order for a task to be well done
- Learned that it takes precision to serve a large group of people

# Student, Young Entrepreneur Academy (Y.E.A) | June 2013- May 2014

- Learned customers, communications, and employees are the center of all business functions
- Learned that employers look for current and potential employees with entrepreneurial skill

#### **Honors & Activities**

- Thomas Jefferson High School Marching Band
- Junior Reserve Officer Training Corps (JROTC)